<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  
  <!-- EN: Magic - Enchanting -->
  <TM_Enchanting.label>Magie - Enchantement</TM_Enchanting.label>
  <!-- EN: Enchanting offers mages the ability to imbue weapons and armor with enhancements.  There are a few things you should know about enchanting:\n\n1. Only mages can enchant!  The process of enchanting requires mana, so mundane pawns will be unable to equip enchanting stones.\n \n2. To enchant an item, your colony must complete the following prerequisites:\n a. Your colony must have a gemcutting workbench, research Enchanting in the research menu under the Magic tab.\n b. Gather raw magicitye; it can be found in any mineable stone, each mining strike has a chance to uncover raw magicyte.\n c. Craft enchanting stones from the gemcutting workbench.\n \n3. Once you've crafted an enchanting gem of your choice, you will need a mage to perform the enchantment.\n a. With a mage selected, right click on the enchanting gem and select the option to equip the gem for enchanting\n b. Once the mage is holding the gem, right click on any weapon or apparel that is on the ground and choose to enchant. The mage performing the enchantment cannot be drafted.\n -->
  <TM_Enchanting.helpText>L'enchantement permet aux mages d'apporter des améliorations aux armes et aux armures.  Il y a quelques choses que vous devez savoir sur l'enchantement :\n\n1. Seuls les mages peuvent enchanter !  Le processus d'enchantement nécessite du mana, donc les colons ordinaires ne pourront pas équiper de pierres d'enchantement.\n\n2. Pour enchanter un objet, votre colonie doit remplir les conditions préalables suivantes :\n a. Votre colonie doit disposer d'une table d'orfèvrerie, faites une recherche sur l'enchantement dans le menu de recherche sous l'onglet Magie.\n b. Rassemblez de la magicite ; elle peut être trouvée dans n'importe quelle pierre exploitable, chaque frappe minière a une chance de trouver de la magicite.\n c. Fabriquez des pierres d'enchantement à partir de la table d'orfèvrerie.\n\n3. Une fois que vous avez fabriqué une gemme enchantée de votre choix, vous aurez besoin d'un mage pour réaliser l'enchantement.\n a. Avec un mage sélectionné, faites un clic droit sur la gemme d'enchantement et sélectionnez l'option pour équiper la gemme pour l'enchantement.\n b. Une fois que le mage tient la gemme, faites un clic droit sur n'importe quelle arme ou vêtement qui se trouve sur le sol et choisissez Enchanter. Le mage qui effectue l'enchantement ne peut pas être mobilisé.	\n</TM_Enchanting.helpText>
  
  <!-- EN: Magic - Enchanting II -->
  <TM_EnchantingII.label>Magie - Enchantement II</TM_EnchantingII.label>
  <!-- EN: Enchanting: Part II\n		\n4. Enchantments are permanent and each item may hold one enchantment of each type.  New enchantments of the same type will replace the existing \nenchantment.  Enchanting an item does not increase the value of the item.  Enchanting an item consumes the enchanting gemstone.  There is\ncurrently no way to extract an enchantment from an item.\n\n5. Raw magicyte (and refined gemstones) may also be purchased from select vendors. The process of deep ore mining, unfortunately, filters out\nthe chance to acquire raw magicyte in this manner. Users of the "quarry" can add magicyte to the extracted minerals, the recommended value is 0.4%\n \n6. If you wish to drop an enchanting stone, select the mage holding the enchanting gem, right click on any open square and select the menu option\nto drop the gem.\n\n7. Item enchantments can be viewed on individual gear by selecting the item on the ground and using the "Enchanted" tab. The collective Enchantments \naffecting a single pawn can be seen in the health tab and a summary of the enchantments will be displayed under a pawn's gear tab.		\n -->
  <TM_EnchantingII.helpText>Enchantement : Partie II\n\n4. Les enchantements sont permanents et chaque objet peut contenir un enchantement de chaque type. De nouveaux enchantements du même type remplaceront l'enchantement existant. L'enchantement d'un objet n'augmente pas la valeur de l'objet. L'enchantement d'un objet consomme la gemme d'enchantement. Il n'y a actuellement aucun moyen d'extraire un enchantement d'un objet.\n\n5. La magicite (et les gemmes raffinées) peuvent également être achetées auprès de certains vendeurs. Le processus d'extraction du minerai en profondeur, malheureusement, élimine la possibilité d'acquérir de la magicite de cette manière. Les utilisateurs de "carrière" peuvent ajouter de la magicite aux minéraux extraits, la valeur recommandée est de 0,4%.\n\n6. Si vous souhaitez déposer une pierre enchantée, sélectionnez le mage qui détient la gemme enchantée, faites un clic droit sur n'importe quelle case ouverte et sélectionnez l'option de menu pour déposer la gemme.\n\n7. Les enchantements des objets peuvent être visualisés sur chaque équipement en sélectionnant l'objet sur le sol et en utilisant l'onglet "Enchanter". Les enchantements communs affectant un seul colon peuvent être vus dans l'onglet santé et un résumé des enchantements sera affiché sous l'onglet équipement du colon.	\n</TM_EnchantingII.helpText>
  
  <!-- EN: Magic - Portals -->
  <TM_Portals.label>Magie - Portails</TM_Portals.label>
  <!-- EN: 1. Only an Arcane mage trained in Gateway magic can activate a portal.\n a. The option to activate a portal only appears when the Arcane mage has enough mana (70%) for activation.\n b. Only a map actively occupied by colonists can be selected.\n \n2. Once activated, any mage can charge the portal; a portal must be charged to use, but any pawn can use it.\n a. Only one pawn at a time may use the portal; each pawn drains the portal by 5% of its maximum energy.\n c. All items are transmitted simultaneously; the cost to transfer items through a portal is 10% of its maximum energy.\n\n3. Only mages can transfer items or deactivate a portal. A portal must be deactivated before it can be reactivated with a new target.\n -->
  <TM_Portals.helpText>1. Seul un mage des arcanes formé à la magie des portails peut activer un portail.\n a. L'option d'activation d'un portail n'apparaît que lorsque le mage des arcanes dispose de suffisamment de mana (70 %) pour l'activation.\n b. Seule une carte occupée activement par des colons peut être sélectionnée.\n\n2. Une fois activé, tout mage peut charger le portail ; un portail doit être chargé pour être utilisé, mais tout colon peut l'utiliser.\n a. Un seul colon à la fois peut utiliser le portail ; chaque colon draine le portail de 5% de son énergie maximum.\n b. Tous les objets sont transmis simultanément ; le coût de transfert des objets à travers un portail est de 10% de son énergie maximum.\n\n3. Seuls les mages peuvent transférer des objets ou désactiver un portail. Un portail doit être désactivé avant de pouvoir être réactivé avec une nouvelle cible.	\n</TM_Portals.helpText>
  
</LanguageData>