<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  
  <!-- EN: cats -->
  <Cat.label>chats</Cat.label>
  <!-- EN: Felis is a genus of small and medium-sized cat species native to most of Africa and south of 60° latitude in Europe and Asia to Indochina. The genus includes the domestic cat. The smallest Felis species is the black-footed cat with a head and body length from 38 to 42 cm (15 to 17 in). The largest is the jungle cat with a head and body length from 62 to 76 cm (24 to 30 in). -->
  <Cat.description>Felis est un genre de petites et moyennes espèces de chats originaires de la plupart de l'Afrique et au sud de 60° de latitude en Europe et en Asie jusqu'à l'Indochine. Le genre comprend le chat domestique. La plus petite espèce de Felis est le chat à pieds noirs avec une longueur de tête et de corps de 38 à 42 cm (15 à 17 in). Le plus grand est le chat des jungles avec une longueur de tête et de corps de 62 à 76 cm (24 à 30 in).</Cat.description>
  
  <!-- EN: cheetahs -->
  <Cheetah.label>guépards</Cheetah.label>
  <!-- EN: The cheetah (Acinonyx jubatus) is a large cat native to Africa and central Iran. It is the fastest land animal, capable of running at 80 to 128 km/h (50 to 80 mph), and as such has several adaptations for speed, including a light build, long thin legs and a long tail. Cheetahs typically reach 67–94 cm (26–37 in) at the shoulder, and the head-and-body length is between 1.1 and 1.5 m (3.6 and 4.9 ft). Adults typically weigh between 20 and 65 kg (44 and 143 lb). Its head is small, rounded, and has a short snout and black tear-like facial streaks. The coat is typically tawny to creamy white or pale buff and is mostly covered with evenly spaced, solid black spots. Four subspecies are recognised. -->
  <Cheetah.description>Le guépard (Acinonyx jubatus) est un grand chat originaire d'Afrique et du centre de l'Iran. C'est l'animal terrestre le plus rapide, capable de courir à 80 à 128 km/h (50 à 80 mph), et a donc plusieurs adaptations pour la vitesse, y compris une construction légère, de longues jambes fines et une longue queue. Les guépards atteignent généralement 67–94 cm (26–37 in) à l'épaule, et la longueur de la tête et du corps est entre 1,1 et 1,5 m (3,6 et 4,9 ft). Les adultes pèsent généralement entre 20 et 65 kg (44 et 143 lb). Sa tête est petite, arrondie, et a un museau court et des stries faciales noires en forme de larmes. Le pelage est généralement fauve à blanc crème ou buff pâle et est principalement couvert de taches noires solides uniformément espacées. Quatre sous-espèces sont reconnues.</Cheetah.description>
  
  <!-- EN: jaguars -->
  <Jaguar.label>jaguars</Jaguar.label>
  <!-- EN: The jaguar (Panthera onca) is a large felid species and the only extant member of the genus Panthera native to the Americas. The jaguar's present range extends from Southwestern United States and Mexico in North America, across much of Central America, and south to Paraguay and northern Argentina in South America. Though there are single cats now living within the Western United States, the species has largely been extirpated from the United States since the early 20th century. It is listed as Near Threatened on the IUCN Red List; and its numbers are declining. Threats include loss and fragmentation of habitat. -->
  <Jaguar.description>Le jaguar (Panthera onca) est une grande espèce de félin et le seul membre existant du genre Panthera originaire des Amériques. L'aire de répartition actuelle du jaguar s'étend du sud-ouest des États-Unis et du Mexique en Amérique du Nord, à travers une grande partie de l'Amérique centrale, et au sud jusqu'au Paraguay et au nord de l'Argentine en Amérique du Sud. Bien qu'il y ait maintenant des chats vivant seuls dans l'ouest des États-Unis, l'espèce a largement été extirpée des États-Unis depuis le début du 20e siècle. Il est classé comme Quasi Menacé sur la Liste Rouge de l'UICN ; et ses nombres sont en déclin. Les menaces comprennent la perte et la fragmentation de l'habitat.</Jaguar.description>
  
  <!-- EN: leopards -->
  <Leopard.label>léopards</Leopard.label>
  <!-- EN: The leopard (Panthera pardus) is one of the five extant species in the genus Panthera, a member of the Felidae. It occurs in a wide range in sub-Saharan Africa, in small parts of Western and Central Asia, on the Indian subcontinent to Southeast and East Asia. It is listed as Vulnerable on the IUCN Red List because leopard populations are threatened by habitat loss and fragmentation, and are declining in large parts of the global range. In Hong Kong, Singapore, Kuwait, Syria, Libya, Tunisia and most likely in Morocco, leopard populations have already been extirpated. Contemporary records suggest that the leopard occurs in only 25% of its historical global range. -->
  <Leopard.description>Le léopard (Panthera pardus) est l'une des cinq espèces existantes du genre Panthera, un membre des Felidae. Il se trouve dans une vaste gamme en Afrique subsaharienne, dans de petites parties de l'Asie occidentale et centrale, sur le sous-continent indien jusqu'en Asie du Sud-Est et de l'Est. Il est classé comme Vulnérable sur la Liste Rouge de l'UICN car les populations de léopards sont menacées par la perte et la fragmentation de l'habitat, et sont en déclin dans de grandes parties de l'aire de répartition mondiale. À Hong Kong, Singapour, Koweït, Syrie, Libye, Tunisie et très probablement au Maroc, les populations de léopards ont déjà été extirpées. Les registres contemporains suggèrent que le léopard ne se trouve que dans 25% de son aire de répartition historique mondiale.</Leopard.description>
  
  <!-- EN: lions -->
  <Lion.label>lions</Lion.label>
  <!-- EN: The lion (Panthera leo) is a species in the family Felidae; it is a muscular, deep-chested cat with a short, rounded head, a reduced neck and round ears, and a hairy tuft at the end of its tail. It is sexually dimorphic; adult male lions have a prominent mane, which is the most recognisable feature of the species. With a typical head-to-body length of 184–208 cm (72–82 in) they are larger than females at 160–184 cm (63–72 in). It is a social species, forming groups called prides. A lion pride consists of a few adult males, related females and cubs. Groups of female lions usually hunt together, preying mostly on large ungulates. The lion is an apex and keystone predator, although some lions scavenge when opportunities occur, and have been known to hunt humans, although the species typically does not. -->
  <Lion.description>Le lion (Panthera leo) est une espèce de la famille des Felidae ; c'est un chat musclé, à poitrine profonde, avec une tête courte et arrondie, un cou réduit et des oreilles rondes, et une touffe de poils à l'extrémité de sa queue. Il est sexuellement dimorphe ; les lions mâles adultes ont une crinière proéminente, qui est la caractéristique la plus reconnaissable de l'espèce. Avec une longueur typique de tête à corps de 184–208 cm (72–82 in) ils sont plus grands que les femelles à 160–184 cm (63–72 in). C'est une espèce sociale, formant des groupes appelés fiertés. Une fierté de lions se compose de quelques mâles adultes, de femelles apparentées et de petits. Les groupes de lionnes chassent généralement ensemble, se nourrissant principalement de grands ongulés. Le lion est un prédateur d'apex et de clé de voûte, bien que certains lions charognent lorsque des opportunités se présentent, et ont été connus pour chasser les humains, même si l'espèce ne le fait pas.</Lion.description>
  
  
  <!-- EN: snow leopards -->
  <SnowLeopard.label>léopards des neiges</SnowLeopard.label>
  <!-- EN: The snow leopard (Panthera uncia), also known as the ounce, is a large cat native to the mountain ranges of Central and South Asia. It is listed as Vulnerable on the IUCN Red List because the global population is estimated to number less than 10,000 mature individuals and is expected to decline about 10% by 2040. It is threatened by poaching and habitat destruction following infrastructural developments. It inhabits alpine and subalpine zones at elevations from 3,000 to 4,500 m (9,800 to 14,800 ft), ranging from eastern Afghanistan, the Himalayas and the Tibetan Plateau, to southern Siberia, Mongolia, and western China. In the countries in the northern part of its range, it also lives at lower elevations. -->
  <SnowLeopard.description>Le léopard des neiges (Panthera uncia), également connu sous le nom d'once, est un grand chat originaire des chaînes de montagnes d'Asie centrale et du sud. Il est classé comme Vulnérable sur la Liste Rouge de l'UICN car la population mondiale est estimée à moins de 10 000 individus matures et devrait diminuer d'environ 10% d'ici 2040. Il est menacé par le braconnage et la destruction de l'habitat suite aux développements infrastructurels. Il habite les zones alpines et subalpines à des altitudes de 3 000 à 4 500 m (9 800 à 14 800 ft), allant de l'Afghanistan oriental, l'Himalaya et le plateau tibétain, à la Sibérie méridionale, la Mongolie et la Chine occidentale. Dans les pays situés dans la partie nord de son aire de répartition, il vit également à des altitudes plus basses.</SnowLeopard.description>
  
  <!-- EN: tigers -->
  <Tiger.label>tigres</Tiger.label>
  <!-- EN: The tiger (Panthera tigris) is the largest extant cat species and a member of the genus Panthera. It is most recognisable for its dark vertical stripes on orange-brown fur with a lighter underside. It is an apex predator, primarily preying on ungulates such as deer and wild boar. It is territorial and generally a solitary but social predator, requiring large contiguous areas of habitat, which support its requirements for prey and rearing of its offspring. Tiger cubs stay with their mother for about two years, before they become independent and leave their mother's home range to establish their own. -->
  <Tiger.description>Le tigre (Panthera tigris) est la plus grande espèce de chat existante et un membre du genre Panthera. Il est le plus reconnaissable par ses rayures verticales foncées sur une fourrure orange-brun avec un dessous plus clair. C'est un prédateur d'apex, se nourrissant principalement d'ongulés tels que les cerfs et les sangliers. Il est territorial et généralement un prédateur solitaire mais social, nécessitant de grandes zones contiguës d'habitat, qui soutiennent ses besoins en proies et l'élevage de sa progéniture. Les petits de tigre restent avec leur mère pendant environ deux ans, avant de devenir indépendants et de quitter le territoire de leur mère pour établir le leur.</Tiger.description>
  
  
</LanguageData>